quoinex.com 2019-07-18

# Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy

              Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy
  IMPORTANT NOTICE FOR RESIDENTS OF JAPAN: This Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy does not apply to
  you if you reside in Japan or if you are using or accessing the Services on behalf of an entity that is
  incorporated, established, or domiciled in Japan. If the preceding sentence applies to you, then you must
  review the Privacy Policy ( 個人情報保護方針 ) provided on the Japanese language version of the Liquid
  website.
  If you are a Japanese citizen not residing in Japan, the Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy set forth below
  applies to you.
Effective Date: 4 September 2018
This Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy (“Policies”), together with our Terms of Use, governs Quoine’s collection,
processing and use of your personal data and our use of cookies and similar technologies. As used in these
Policies, "Quoine", "we", "us" or "our" refers to Quoine Pte. Ltd., a company organized under the laws of
Singapore. These Policies constitute a part of the Terms of Use to which you have previously agreed by
registering for our Services and accessing our websites.
The governing language of these Policies is English. Any other language translation is provided for convenience
only. The “Privacy Policy” ( 個人情報保護方針 ) written in Japanese available on the Japanese language
version of the Liquid website is not a translation of these Policies and is applicable only to users who reside in
Japan.
Please contact us with questions, comments, or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy
and/or practices at privacy@liquid.com.
1 ACCEPTANCE OF POLICIES AND UPDATES
By clicking a checkbox or a button that contains words such as “I Agree” when these Policies are presented to
you or, if earlier, by accessing or using any Services, you, you signify your acceptance to the terms of this
Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy. If you do not agree with or are not comfortable with any aspect of these
Policies, you should immediately stop accessing and using the Services. You may also contact us with
questions, comments, or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy and/or practices at
privacy@liquid.com.
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy and/or Cookies Policy at any time, and when required by law,
we will notify you of changes to these Policies. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email
(sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our Sites prior to the change
becoming effective.
2 DEFINITIONS
Certain capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy have the following meanings.
“Account” means an individual or corporate account for use of the Services opened by you in accordance with
the Terms of Use.
                                                                                                    v1.02 (2018.09.04)

“Data Privacy Laws” means data protection laws applicable to Quoine, including without limitation the
Singapore Personal Data Protection Act 2012 and the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679, and
their respective successors or implementing texts.
“Personal Data” means any information that directly or indirectly can be used to identify a natural person.
Personal Data does not include anonymized and/or aggregated data that does not identify a specific user.
“Services” has the meaning given in our Terms of Use.
“Terms of Use” means the Terms of Use posted on the Sites, which govern your use of the Services.
“Sites” has the meaning given in our Terms of Use.
3 PRIVACY POLICY
Quoine respects and is committed to protecting your privacy. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to describe:
   •   The Personal Data we collect and how we may use such data;
   •   How and why we may disclose your Personal Data to third parties;
   •   The transfer of your Personal Data outside your country of residence;
   •   Your rights concerning your Personal Data;
   •   The security measures we use to protect and prevent the loss, misuse, or alteration of Personal Data;
       and
   •   Quoine’s retention of your Personal Data.
In cases where we require your consent to process your personal information, we will ask for your consent to
the collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Data as described further below. We may provide
additional disclosures or additional information about the data collection, use and sharing practices of specific
Services. These notices may supplement or clarify Quoine’s privacy practices or may provide you with
additional choices about how Quoine processes your data.
3.1 Collection of Personal Information
We collect Personal Data to provide you with our Services. You are free to choose whether to provide us with
the types of Personal Data requested, but we may not be able to offer you some or all our Services when you
choose not to share certain information with us.
For example, we collect Personal Data which is required under law to open an account, to link a bank account,
or to execute a transaction. We also collect Personal Data when you use or request information about our
Services, subscribe to marketing communications, request support, complete surveys, or communicate with us.
We may also collect Personal Data from you offline, such as when you attend one of our events or when you
contact customer support. We may use this information in combination with other information we collect
about you as set forth in this Privacy Policy.
Personal Data we collect may include the following:
Information you provide to us. We collect information that you provide directly to us through the Sites or by
e-mail, phone, or any other medium. This may include:
   •   Personal identification information, such as your full name, home address, email address, date of birth,
       age, nationality, gender, signature, and photographs.
   •   Formal identification information, such as tax identification number, passport number and details,
       driver’s license details, national identity card details, photograph identification cards, and immigration
       visa information.
   •   Account information, such as your username, password, account settings and preferences.
                                                                                                      v1.02 (2018.09.04)

  •    Financial information, such as bank account numbers, bank statement, virtual currency wallet addresses,
       trading data, and tax identification.
  •    Residence verification information, such as utility bill details, bank statements, or similar information.
Information we collect when you use our services. We also automatically collect information about your
computer, device and browsing activity when you access the Sites or use Services. This information may
include:
  •    Device Information, such as the hardware, operating system, and browser used by you, and any other
       information that is automatically collected about your device.
  •    Location Information, such as your IP address and/or domain name, any external page that referred you
       to us, and any other information that is automatically collected via analytics systems providers to
       determine your location.
  •    Log Information, such as device-specific information, location information, system activity, any internal
       and external information related to Site pages that you visit, and any other that is generated by your use
       of the Sites and Services that is automatically collected and stored in our server logs.
  •    Account Information – Information that is generated by your account activity, such as trading activity,
       order activity, deposits, withdrawals, and account balances.
Information we collect from other sources. We may collect information from third party partners, public
authorities, public websites, social media and other public sources, which may include information related to
your identification, location, reputation, business activities, and other personal details.
3.2 How We Use Your Personal Information
We only use your Personal Data if we have a proper reason for doing so. Unless we receive permission from
you, we will not use your Personal Data for purposes other than those set forth below.
Legal Obligations. We process certain information to comply with our legal obligations:
  •    To maintain legal and regulatory compliance: We are required by law to collect and use your Personal
       Data in connection with certain of our core Services. For example, we must identify and verify users to
       comply with anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism laws in various
       jurisdictions. For this purpose, we use third parties to verify your identity by comparing the Personal
       Data you provided against third-party databases and public records. If you do not provide this Personal
       Data, you will not be allowed to use our Services.
  •    To ensure network and information security: We process your Personal Data to enhance security,
       monitor and verify identity or service access, combat spam or other malware or security risks and to
       comply with applicable security laws and regulations. The threat landscape on the internet is constantly
       evolving, which makes it more important than ever that we have accurate and up-to-date information
       about your use of our Services. Without processing your Personal Data, we may not be able to ensure
       the security of our Services.
Contractual Obligations. We process certain information to be able to perform our obligations under our
contract with you:
  •    To provide the Services: We process your Personal Data to provide the Services to you, including to open
       an account and to process your transactions. We cannot provide you with Services without such
       information.
                                                                                                       v1.02 (2018.09.04)

  •    To provide communications: We send administrative or account-related information to you to keep you
       updated about our Services, inform you of relevant security issues or updates, or provide other
       transaction-related information. Without such communications, you may not be aware of important
       developments relating to your account that may affect how you can use our Services.
  •    To provide customer service: We process your Personal Data to resolve user questions or disputes, to
       collect fees, or to troubleshoot problems. Without processing your Personal Data for such purposes, we
       cannot respond to your requests and ensure your uninterrupted use of the Services.
  •    To ensure quality control: We process your Personal Data for quality control and staff training to make
       sure we continue to provide you with accurate information and well-functioning services. If we do not
       process Personal Data for quality control purposes, you may experience issues on the Services such as
       inaccurate transaction records or other interruptions.
Legitimate Interests. We process certain information based on our legitimate business interests in connection
with our provision of the Services to you:
  •    To ensure network and information security (as described in Legal Obligations above).
  •    To enforce our terms of use and other agreements: Due to the importance of information we handle,
       such as your identification and financial data, it is very important for us and our customers that we
       actively monitor, investigate, prevent and mitigate any potentially prohibited or illegal activities or
       violations of our Terms of Use, and enforce our agreements with third parties, and violations of our
       Terms of Use or other agreements related to the Services. We may use any of your Personal Data
       collected on our Services for these purposes.
  •    For research and development purposes: We process your Personal Data to better understand the way
       you use and interact with the Services. In addition, we use such information to customize, measure, and
       improve the Services and the content and layout of the Sites and applications, and to develop new
       services. Without such processing, we cannot ensure your continued enjoyment of our Services.
  •    To enhance your website experience: We process your Personal Data to provide a personalized
       experience and to implement the preferences you request. Without such processing, we may not be
       able to ensure your continued enjoyment of part or all of our Services.
  •    To facilitate corporate acquisitions, mergers, or transactions: We may process any information regarding
       your account and use of our Services as is necessary in the context of corporate acquisitions, mergers, or
       other corporate transactions. You have the option of closing your account if you do not wish to have
       your Personal Data processed for such purposes.
  •    To engage in marketing activities: Based on your communication preferences, we may send you
       marketing communications to inform you about our events or our partner events, to deliver targeted
       marketing, and to provide you with promotional offers based on your communication preferences. We
       use information about your usage of our Services and your contact information to provide marketing
       communications. We may also share Personal Data with third parties to help us with our marketing and
       promotional projects or sending marketing communications. For example, we may participate in
       Facebook’s Custom Audience and Google’s Customer Match programs, in which we may provide certain
       Personal Data to Facebook and Google for the purpose of delivering targeted advertisements to other
       internet users. You can opt-out of our marketing activities at any time by contacting us at the following
       email address: privacy@liquid.com.
3.3 Automated Decision Making
We may make automated decisions on certain matters, such as to fulfill our obligations imposed by law (such
as to verify your identity), to detect fraudulent or prohibited activities, or to determine whether you are eligible
for certain of our Services. If you disagree with the decision you are entitled to contest this by contacting us at
following email address: privacy@liquid.com.
                                                                                                     v1.02 (2018.09.04)

3.4 Our Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies
Please see Part 4 (Cookies Policy) below for a description of how we use cookies and similar technologies on
the Sites.
3.5 Disclosures to Third Parties
We take care to allow your Personal Data to be accessed only by those who need to perform their tasks and
duties, and to share your Personal Data only with third parties who have a legitimate purpose for accessing it.
Except in the following circumstances, we will not sell, exchange, or share your Personal Data without your
consent:
  •    We may share your Personal Data with third party identity verification and transaction monitoring
       services to assist in the prevention of fraud and other illegal activities and to fulfill our obligations under
       anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism laws and regulations. This allows
       Quoine to confirm your identity by comparing the Personal Data you provide us to public records and
       other third-party databases and to monitor transactions to fulfil our legal and regulatory obligations to
       report suspicious activities.
  •    We may share your Personal Data with service providers under contract who provide professional
       services (such as legal and accounting advisors) or help with parts of our business operations (such as
       marketing, payment and technology services). Our contracts will require these service providers to use
       your Personal Data only in connection with the services they perform for us and prohibit them from
       selling your Personal Data to anyone else.
  •    We may share your Personal Data with financial institutions and payment services providers with which
       we partner to process payments you have authorized.
  •    We may share your Personal Data with companies or other entities that we plan to merge with or be
       acquired by. If any such a combination occurs, then we will require that the new combined entity follow
       this Privacy Policy with respect to your Personal Data. You will receive prior notice of any change in
       applicable policies.
  •    We may share your information with companies or other entities that purchase Quoine’s assets
       pursuant to a court-approved sale under applicable bankruptcy laws or where we are required to share
       your information pursuant to applicable insolvency laws.
  •    We may share your information with law enforcement, government officials or regulators, or other third
       parties when we are compelled to do so by a subpoena, court order, or similar legal procedure, or when
       we believe in good faith that the disclosure of Personal Data is necessary to prevent physical harm or
       financial loss, to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to report suspected illegal activity, or to
       investigate violations of our Terms of Use or any other applicable policies.
  •    In addition, from time to time we may request your consent to share your information with third parties
       in certain other circumstances. Such requests may be presented to you in our Terms of Use, an email
       from us to you, or otherwise through the Services.
3.6 Consent to International Transfers of Personal Data
As a global company, we may store and process your Personal Data in our facilities in various locations,
including Japan, Singapore, and Vietnam. This Privacy Policy applies regardless of the location in which we
store and process your Personal Data.
We transfer Personal Data to service providers that process data in Ireland and Japan for the specific purposes
of performing identity verification and other screening, to enable us to prevent fraud and to comply with our
know-your-customer obligations under anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism laws
and regulations.
                                                                                                         v1.02 (2018.09.04)

We transfer Personal Data to service providers located in the United States for the specific purposes of
delivering emails and targeted marketing. When we send emails, Personal Data may pass through our service
provider’s data centers in Japan, India, and/or the United Kingdom for geo-forwarding to the United States.
By accepting this Privacy Policy, you specifically and voluntarily consent to the transfer of your personal
information to each of the countries specified in the preceding paragraphs. Some of these countries might not
have protections in place for personal data as extensive as those within your country of residence. However,
we require our service providers to treat your personal information in strict confidence and to use appropriate
security measures to protect it. We also require them to uphold all of our other obligations under this Privacy
Policy.
You may revoke your consent to this section at any time by contacting us at privacy@liquid.com.
3.7 Your Rights
You have certain rights concerning your Personal Data under Data Privacy Laws, which you can exercise by
contacting us at privacy@liquid.com. These rights include:
  •     Access: You have the right to request that we provide you a copy of your Personal Data held by us. In
        accordance with applicable Data Privacy Laws, we may request that you specify the information or
        processing activities to which your request relates before we provide you with a copy of your Personal
        Data.
  •     Correction: You have the right to request that any incomplete or inaccurate Personal Data we hold
        about you is corrected.
  •     Erasure: You have the right to ask us to delete or remove Personal Data in certain circumstances. There
        are also certain exceptions where we may refuse a request for erasure, such as in cases where the
        Personal Data is required for compliance with law or in connection with pending legal claims.
  •     Restriction: You have the right to ask us to suspend the processing of certain of your Personal Data
        about you if (a) you dispute the accuracy of the Personal Data and wish for us to verify the accuracy,
        (b) your Personal Data has been unlawfully processed, (c) we no longer need the Personal Data, but you
        need us to retain such Personal Data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim, or (d) you have
        objected to our processing your Personal Data, pending the verification of whether our legitimate
        grounds for processing the Personal Data override your rights.
  •     Data Portability: You may obtain or request the transfer of certain of your Personal Data to another
        party if both (a) our lawful basis for processing the Personal Data was based on either your consent or
        our performance of our obligations under our contract with you, and (b) the processing was carried out
        by automated means.
  •     Objection: If we are processing your Personal Data on the basis of our legitimate interests for doing so,
        you have the right to provide specific reasons why you object to such processing. You also have the right
        to object where we are processing your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes.
  •     Automated Decisions: You may contest any automated decision made about you where this has a legal
        or similar significant effect and ask for it to be reconsidered.
  •     Right to Submit a Complaint: If you believe that we have infringed your rights, we encourage you to
        contact us first at privacy@liquid.com so that we can try to resolve the issue or dispute informally. You
        can also submit a complaint about our processing of your Personal Data to the relevant data protection
        authority. You can submit a complaint in the country where you live or work or in the place where the
        alleged breach of the applicable Data Privacy Laws has taken place.
                                                                                                     v1.02 (2018.09.04)

3.8 Security of Personal Data
We use a variety of security measures to ensure the confidentiality of your Personal Data and to protect your
Personal Data from loss, theft, unauthorized access, misuse, alteration or destruction. For example, we use
computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, we enforce physical access controls to our
buildings and files, and we authorize access to Personal Data only for those employees who require it to fulfill
their job responsibilities.
However, we cannot guarantee that loss, theft, unauthorized access, misuse, alteration or destruction of your
Personal Data will not occur. Please take adequate measures to protection your Personal Data. When
registering to use our Services, it is important to choose a password of sufficient length and complexity and to
keep this password a secret. Please notify us immediately if you become aware of any unauthorized access to
or use of your account.
Furthermore, we cannot ensure the security or confidentiality of Personal Data that you transmit to us or
receive from us via the internet or wireless connection, including email, phone, or SMS. If you have reason to
believe that your data is no longer secure, please contact us at the email address, mailing address or telephone
number listed at the end of this Privacy Policy.
3.9 Retention of Personal Data
We retain Personal Data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, subject
to our own legal and regulatory obligations. The criteria we may use to determine the retention period for
certain categories of data includes:
   •    how long you have had an Account;
   •    whether there are contractual or legal obligations that exist that require us to retain the data for a
        certain period of time;
   •    whether there is any ongoing legal or financial claim that relates to your relationship with us;
   •    whether any applicable law, statute, or regulation allows for a specific retention period; and
   •    what the expectation for retention was at the time the data was provided to us.
Except where prohibited by law, this period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with for so long as
is necessary for audit or other accounting or regulatory purposes. When Personal Data are no longer needed
we have procedures either to destroy, delete, erase or convert it to an anonymous form.
After you have terminated your use of our Services, we reserve the right to maintain your Personal Data as part
of our standard back up procedures in an aggregated format.
3.10 Children’s Personal Information
We do not knowingly request to collect Personal Data from any person under the age of 18. If a user
submitting Personal Data is suspected of being younger than 18 years of age, we will require the user to close
his or her account. We will also take steps to delete the Personal Data as soon as possible. Please notify us if
you know of any individuals under the age of 18 using our Services so we can act to prevent access to our
Services.
4 COOKIES POLICY
4.1 Description of Cookies
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used
to allow websites to work properly or more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the
website.
There are two general categories of cookies. “First-party cookies” cookies are set directly by us. “Third-party
cookies” are set by a third party, and that third party can recognize your computer both when it visits the Sites
and when it visits certain other websites and/or mobile apps.
                                                                                                     v1.02 (2018.09.04)

Cookies can remain on your computer or mobile device for different periods of time. Some cookies are “session
cookies”, which exist only while your browser is open and expire once you close your browser. Other cookies
are “persistent cookies”, which survive after your browser is closed. They can be used by websites to recognize
your computer when you open your browser and browse the internet again.
More information on cookies and their use can be found at www.aboutcookies.org or
www.allaboutcookies.org.
4.2 Why We Use Cookies
When you access our Services, we or companies we work with may place cookies on your computer or other
device. These technologies help us better understand user behavior and inform us about which parts of the
Sites people have visited.
We use cookies to:
   •   track traffic flow and patterns of travel in connection with the Sites;
   •   understand the total number of visitors to the Sites on an ongoing basis and the types of internet
       browsers (e.g. Firefox, Chrome or Internet Explorer) and operating systems (e.g. Windows or Mac OS)
       used by our visitors;
   •   monitor the performance of the Sites and to continually improve them;
   •   customize and enhance your online experience; and
   •   enable us and third-party to advertise both on and off the Sites.
4.3 Categories of Cookies We Use
We use the following categories of cookies:
   •   Strictly Necessary Cookies: These cookies are necessary because they enable you to move around our
       Sites and use certain features on our Services. For example, strictly necessary cookies allow you to
       access secure areas. Without these cookies, some Services cannot be provided.
   •   Functionality Cookies: These cookies allow us to remember the choices you make and to tailor our
       Services so we can provide relevant content to you. For example, a functionality cookie can remember
       your preferences (e.g., country or language selection), or your username.
   •   Performance/Analytics Cookies: These cookies collect information about how you use a website. For
       example, a performance/analytics cookie will collect information about which pages you go to most
       often, how much time you spend on that page, or if you get error messages from certain pages. These
       cookies do not gather information that identifies you. The information these cookies collect is
       anonymous and is only used to improve how our Services work.
   •   Advertising and Tracking Cookies: Our Sites may feature advertising. We may allow third party
       companies, including advertising companies, to place cookies on our Sites. These cookies enable such
       companies to track your activity across various sites where they display ads and record your activities so
       they can show ads that they consider relevant to you as you browse the Internet. These cookies also
       allow us and third parties to know whether you have seen an ad or a type of ad, and how long it has
       been since you last saw it. This information may be used for frequency capping purposes, to help tailor
       the ads you see, and to measure the effectiveness of ads. These cookies are anonymous – they store
       information about the content you are browsing, but not about who you are.
                                                                                                   v1.02 (2018.09.04)

4.4 Other Similar Technologies We Use
In addition to cookies, we may use other similar technologies such as web beacons to track users of our
Services. Web beacons, or “clear gifs”, are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies.
They are used to track the online movements of web users.
In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive or device, clear gifs are embedded
invisibly on web pages. We and our third-party service provider employ web beacons for the reasons stated
above (under "4.2 – Why We Use Cookies"), but primarily to help us better manage content on our Services by
informing us which content is effective.
4.5 Avoiding and Disabling Cookies
You have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies, and instructions for exercising this right are
given below. However, please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full
functionality of our Sites.
   •    Our Cookies. Most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be
        found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser.
   •    Do Not Track. Some Internet browsers – like Chrome, Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari – include the
        ability to transmit "Do Not Track" or "DNT" signals. Since uniform standards for "DNT" signals have not
        been adopted, our Sites may not be able to process or respond to "DNT" signals.
   •    Advertising Cookies. To opt-out of third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use
        targeting/advertising cookies, go to http://www.aboutads.info/choices. Once you click the link, you may
        choose to opt-out of such advertising from all participating advertising companies or only advertising
        provided by specific advertising entities. For more information about third-party advertising networks
        and similar entities that use these technologies, please see http://www.aboutads.info/consumers.
                                                                                                     v1.02 (2018.09.04)
